More Suggestions for Healthy Living

Tricks to Improve Brain Power

Practice mentally what you need to do: rehearsing the activity uses most of the same brain connections, which are switched on during the real thing.

Scientist experts believe that the brain is most active right after you wake up or before you go to sleep, so use these times to think about solutions and be creative.

So that you don't lose things as easily, focus your attention to try to remember where you put you put them. Pay attention to the time of the day, the weather, the day’s headline news or what you are wearing at the moment. You can also create a funny picture with the object, so that will come to mind when you are trying to recall where you put it.

Researchers are now saying that you need to continue to be actually active as you age, try learning a new skill, a new language, how to play a musical instrument or learn to be involved in a new type of activity such as putting together puzzles. The Center of Disease Control and Prevention recommends that all adults get a

minimum  of  150  minutes  per  week  of  moderate  aerobic  activity  such  as  a  brisk  walk  per  week. Sedentary living, not high cholesterol is the single biggest factor in heart attack deaths and perhaps also mental decline as we age.

Foods for Healthy Living

Eat foods that are rich in brain boosting beta-carotene. Omega 3s boosts your heart health, and can be found in salmon, walnuts, soy and flaxseed. Good hear health boosts brain power. Fiber: about 21–38 grams a day helps the digestive tract and control cholesterol

levels. Legumes which are low in fat food like the peas and beans family are excellent sources of proteins, fiber and flavor. Excellent served as a side dish.

Quotes

“Approach love and cooking with reckless abandon!” Dalai Lama

“Enthusiasm is contagious. Be a carrier.”

Healthy Snacks

They say that when you work out, your muscles are torn down and built back up. The body's natural healing process restores your muscles to a stronger state than they were before. Healthy protein snacks can help this recovery process.

10 High-Protein Power Snacks

Numerous studies, including one published in the Journal of the American Medical Association have shown that skipping high-protein foods may lead to overeating and is often one of the biggest causes of excess weight gain. And, as any devoted exerciser knows, protein is essential for the growth and repair of muscle and organs, especially after a hard workout. Fill up on powerful protein with these tasty options.

High-Protein Snack: Eggs

One large egg contains 6 grams of protein and only 70 calories. If you're concerned about cholesterol, many egg substitutes on the market offer lower-cholesterol alternatives that still pack a protein punch. One of the best ways to eat eggs is hard-boiled. Keep a bowl of them in your fridge for an instant, healthy snack or an addition to a larger meal.

High-Protein Snack: Nuts

Whether you go for almonds, cashews, walnuts, pistachios, or any of the other varieties, whole, raw nuts are a healthy high-protein snack. If you're concerned about calories, limit your nut intake to a handful or two, and remember that although nuts are high in fat, it's healthy monounsaturated fat, which doesn't clog arteries and is an essential part of a healthy diet. Plus, nuts are high in fiber, and keep you feeling full longer.

High-Protein Snack: Greek Yogurt

The yogurt's power comes from its protein. Greek yogurt contains 15–20 grams of protein in a 6 oz serving versus 9 grams in regular yogurt.

High-Protein Snack: Turkey

When you're going for lean protein, nothing beats low-calorie turkey. Three oz of turkey provides 25 grams of protein for only 140 calories.

High-Protein Snack: Protein Shakes

Simply combine whey protein with nonfat milk, frozen fruit, all-natural nut butter, or whatever other healthful ingredients sound good to you, and you have a healthy meal replacement or snack.

High-Protein Snack: Cottage Cheese

Cottage cheese is an excellent protein source with a half-cup of low-fat cottage cheese providing 14 grams of protein for only 81 calories. Paired with fruit or plain, it makes a terrific snack when you want to stay full between meals.

High-Protein Snack: Lentils

Lentils pack a powerful punch of protein, fiber, and minerals while containing comparatively few calories and almost no fat. A cup of cooked lentils offers 22 grams of protein, about 300 calories, and less than 1 gram of fat.

High-Protein Snack: Tofu

Tofu or soy bean curd is another excellent high-protein meal base and source of healthy fats and nutrients. Because it absorbs flavors so well and can be cut into cubes, strips, or chunks, it can be prepared in a variety of ways.

High-Protein Snack : Nut Butter

Almond, cashew, peanut and other nut butters are high-protein foods with about two tbsp providing 7 grams of protein. And, although nut butter contains fat, it can be part of a healthy diet when eaten in small amounts. Just remember not to slather it on crackers; spread it on carrot or celery sticks for healthy snacking instead.

High-Protein Snack : Pumpkin Seeds

Pumpkins are full of fiber, vitamins, and body-boosting carotenoids, but it turns out tiny pumpkin seeds might pack even more of a nutritional punch. With 8 grams of protein in just one oz, pumpkin seeds or pepitas are also very rich in minerals, including potassium, manganese, and iron. Just take heed: Pumpkin seeds are calorie-dense, so do your healthy snacking in moderation.

– Source: everyday health.com

5 Ways To Turn Off Your Hunger Switch

Research reveals that it’s your brain and not your stomach that is Command Central for weight management. It’s the single most exciting breakthrough in weight management in the last-plus 10 years and yet, no one is talking about it,” says Doug Kalman, PhD. F.A.C.N., director of the phase I Clinical Research unit of Miami Research Associates, a research site that’s been part of some of the biggest health breakthrough in the last 25 years.

The breakthrough came when researchers finally discovered that the brain uses a type of messaging system very similar to “texting” to determine what to eat, and when you are hungry and when you are not.

“This understanding now allows people to take a simple approach to weight management that does not ask them to change their life style,” says Kalman. “ It is something that everyone can do.” When used in tandem with smart eating and exercise, bolstering your personal will power with a brain that is also on board can boost weight loss goals big time. Here are a few simple strategies to help you get started.

FILL UP WITH FIBER AND WATER. Fiber and water trigger feelings of fullness and reduce hunger by sending a “YOU ARE FULL!” text to the brain.

Flip your switch: Have a cup of clear soup broth with veggies 15 minutes before a meal, or drink a fiber supplement stirred into a glass of water for similar effect.

GET A GOOD NIGHT’S SLEEP. People who get inadequate sleep, that is, six hours or less per night, have increased amounts of hormone ghrelin when they wake up the next morning, says Christopher Nolte, M. D., a neurologist who hold certifications from both the American Board of Sleep Medicine and The American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology. Think of the ghrelin as the text that the stomach sends to the brain, saying it needs food. “When the brain gets the message, it texts back, “OK, let’s eat,’ and you typically go looking for carbs,” says Nolte. “The reality is that you don’t need to eat carbs right then, despite what your brain is telling you.”

Flip your switch: “Allow yourself seven hours or more sleep” says Nolte. And when you get some carb cravings, have water or a cup of brewed tea, and fiber instead.

PUNCH UP YOUR POLYPHENOLS. Green and red teas, along with other polyphenol-rich foods and supplements (most notably those with high levels of two types of polyphenols-anthocyanins and stilbenes) have been shown to be very good at turning off the hunger switch. Stilbenes are found in grapes, blueberries and cranberries. The best-known stilbene is the anti-aging comb resveratrol, mostly found in red grapes and red wine. Authocyanins are present in popular superfruits such as acai berries, blueberries and red grapes and are also found in red wine. In a study published in Molecular Nutrition and Food Research from the US Department of Agriculture found that purified berry anthocyanins normalized the fat levels in mice that were fed a high-fat diet. Scientists attribute this effect to the ability of anthocyanins to assist cell burning energy, inducing satiety and, ultimately, turning off the hunger switch.

Flip your switch: Increase you intake of green and red teas and berries. Or, take 200 mg of resveratrol in supplement form daily.

DON’T BUY THESE BAD BOYS. Some ingredients turn on your hunger switch, so it pays to read labels. Some of the worst offenders: high-fructose corn syrup (HFCS) and palmitic acid (the main fat in palm oil, palm kernel oil and saturated fat in beef). These troublemakers stop the hormones leptin and insulin, two of the brain most important “hunger messengers,” from reaching Command Central. When leptin and insulin, are blocked from the brain, the brain cells tell you to keep on eating, which can mean making the difference between having a few chips and eating half the bag. In fact, in a study published in The Journal of Clinical Investigation, researchers from UT Southwestern Medical Center in Dallas found that palmitic acid’s ability to block leptin and insulin was so great that it that it may be the root cause of both obesity and Type 2 diabetes.

Flip your switch: Choose whole, fresh unadulterated foods. Shop the perimeter of your supermarket, where the least processed foods are found. Reduce your intake of beef and/or opt for “grass-fed” beef, which contains less of the problematic saturated fat.

POWER YOUR PROTEIN. While increasing your consumption of protein can satiate your appetite, two of protein’s building blocks, namely the amino acids tyrosine and 5-hydroxytrytophan (5-HTP), have been identified as the most crucial to relay messages to the brain. Simply stated, tyrosine and 5-HTP work as neuromessengers, speeding up messages to the brain that turn off the desire for food. That means with tyrosine and 5-HTP, whether in food or supplements, craving end faster and fewer calories are consumed.

Flip your switch: Take 150–250 mg of tyrosine and 100–200 mg of 5-HTP daily. In addition, protein will turn off your hunger switch to a greater extend than carbohydrates or fat, so replacing some carbs with protein may help to reduce your overall caloric intake. Eat a minimum of 20 g of protein at each main meal.

– http://www.gnclivewell.com.au/blog-details.asp?id=284

Preface

Brock and Company, Inc. continues to celebrate its success since 1927 in constant food service industry innovation. It is exciting adjusting to taste, habits and style change opportunities.

Lynmar Brock Sr. in 1927 determined to offer factory workers a boxed lunch containing a ham sandwich, salad, slice of spiced lunch meat, slice of American cheese, sweet pickles, dessert, a cup of cream cabbage, spiced cake with lemon icing and an apple, all for 25 cents. The depression of the 1930’s was a demanding time for the country, but Brock’s Box Lunches continued to expand offering even more at a greater value.

The War years were a time of expansion of manufacturing. The company moved into a new and larger plant on December 6, 1941 and was well prepared to service the increased demands of a country at war. The company soon further expanded into corporate food service operation where on site chefs made it possible to increase the freshness and variety of food offered.

In the following years, Brock operated restaurants that combined freshness and variety with ever-changing menu selections. More recently, adding food service for private and independent school students has provided the increased ability and incentive to serve fresh, local and healthful foods to not only students, but with the lessons learned there, to an increasing broad range of corporations and enterprises.

Today the food offerings at each corporate and school location are prepared on site. This allows Brock to support and serve a variety of foods to satisfy individual desires, needs and demands. The company now operates throughout the eastern United States along with a Rocky Mountain division.

Brock and Company carries on with the same foresight and imagination of Lynmar Brock, Sr. and with his conclusion that change is wonderful and exciting.

This cookbook is one reflection of the quality of food, the professionalism and the experience of its preparers that make up Brock and Company. We hope you will find the recipes delicious and nutritious and wish to learn more about how we can provide quality and value to your corporate or school food service systems.

Change is wonderful. Change is exciting. Remember the past. Embrace the future.

—Lynmar Brock, Jr., President of Brock and Company, Inc. 1962–2007

Introduction

“The doctor of the future will give no medicine, but will interest his patients in the care of the human body, in diet and in the cause and prevention of disease”. This is a quote from the famous brilliant inventor Thomas Edison, who had more than a thousand patents to his name.

In this cookbook we not only have a collection of delicious recipes provided by our associates, but we also include information and recommendations for healthy a life style, with plenty of exercise, fresh air and healthy eating.

We start with the premise that everyone knows that smoking has been proven very detrimental to good health. So, that if you are smoking, it would be wise to look into some smoke secession programs, available. Many of these programs are available through your health insurance provider.

Many studies have been done showing the great benefit of doing regular cardio type exercises for at least 150 minutes a week in, including a good amount of stretching before starting. Studies have also shown that exercising in the morning burns more fat cells than doing it in the afternoon, because during sleep time fat cells accumulate, so doing so in the morning seems to be more beneficial, if you are trying to lose weight. Exercise also helps to improve the brain cognitive function, because it produces more synapses in the brain.

Being overweight is a problem in our time because many people are unaware of the amount of sugar they consume on average. Sugar then turns into fat cells. Our ancestors would consumed an average of 5 pounds of sugar a year, today it is said that on average we consume 10 times that much.

The information in this cookbook provides nutrition facts, for one serving only, indicating the number of calories, total fats, saturated fats, cholesterol, sodium, carbohydrates, proteins vitamin A and calcium content.

The information in this cookbook is for educational purpose only and not to be construed as medical advice. Consult a medical practitioner before making any major life style changes.

— Claudie Brock, June 23, 2014

Chocolate

Chocolate and its main ingredient, cocoa, appear to reduce risk factors for heart disease. Flavanols in cocoa beans have antioxidant effects that reduce cell damage implicated in heart disease. Flavanols also help lower blood pressure and improve vascular function. Dark chocolate contains more flavanols than does milk chocolate. One caveat: The evidence for the healthy benefits of flavanol-rich chocolate comes mostly from short-term and uncontrolled studies. More research will be needed to confirm chocolate's role in heart health.

In the meantime, if you want to add chocolate to your diet, do so in moderation. Why? Most commercial chocolate has ingredients that add fat, sugar and calories. And too much can contribute to weight gain, a risk factor for high blood pressure, heart disease and diabetes.

Choose dark chocolate with cocoa content of 65 percent or higher. Limit yourself to no more than 3 oz (85 grams) a day, which is the amount shown in studies to be helpful. Because this amount may provide up to 450 calories, you may want to cut calories in other areas or step up the exercise to compensate.

– content from the Mayo Clinic